<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd">
<article lang="">
   <para>p. 34-35</para>
   <para>1.  It causes the base costs for goods, which is the starting point for both the producer's logistics and the price tag the consumer sees</para>
   <para>2.  Land, Labor, Capital, Entrepreneurship; scarcity is the measure of a Factor's availability.</para>
   <para>3.  A "free lunch" still costs some amount of at least one of the Factors of Production</para>
   <para>8.  µEconomics - The economic systems of an individual; Macronomics - The economic systems of a group, typically the group of all non-economically-isolated people.</para>
   <para>11. </para>
   <para>$900 |                                   $860</para>
   <para>$850 |                                  |˜˜˜˜˜˜|</para>
   <para>$800 |                                  |        |</para>
   <para>$750 |                                  |        |</para>
   <para>$700 |                                  |        |</para>
   <para>$650 |            $605              |        |</para>
   <para>$600 |          |–––––|             |        |</para>
   <para>$550 |          |          |   $488  |        |</para>
   <para>$500 |          |          |   _____|        |</para>
   <para>$450 | $424 |          |   |         |        |</para>
   <para>$400 | |˜˜˜˜˜˜|          |   |         |        |</para>
   <para>$350 | |        |          |   |         |        |</para>
   <para>$300 | |        |          |   |         |        |</para>
   <para>$250 | |        |          |   |         |        |</para>
   <para>$200 | |        |          |   |         |        |</para>
   <para>$150 | |        |          |   |         |        |</para>
   <para>$100 | |        |          |   |         |        |</para>
   <para>$50   | |        |          |   |         |        |</para>
   <para>$0     L––––––––––––––––––––––––––––––––––––</para>
   <para>             HS     Col       HS    Col</para>
   <para>                 1979              2004</para>
   <para>13. </para>
   <para>Downtown:</para>
   <para>  +: More Business; High traffic; Able to charge more </para>
   <para>  –: Higher Upkeep and/or Less Space; no patio; requires more soundproofing; less windows; less visible; no parking</para>
   <para>Quiet Neighborhood:</para>
   <para>  +: Lower Upkeep and/or More Space; able to have patio; probably doesn't require soundproofing; windows possibly w/ view; more visible; parking </para>
   <para>  –: Less Business; must charge less; if in the hood, requires most soundproofing</para>
   <para>14. oops..</para>
   <para>–––––––––––––T––––––––––––––T–––––––––––––––––T–––––––––––––––––––––T–––––––––––––––––––––––––T–––––––––––T</para>
   <para>|            | Vet. Surgeon | Pizza Delivery  |  Sidewalk Musician  | Ministry of Silly Walks |   Sleep   |</para>
   <para>+––––––––––––+––––––––––––––+–––––––––––––––––+–––––––––––––––––––––+–––––––––––––––––––––––––+–––––––––––+</para>
   <para>|            |MD training,  |Cars,            |Music,               |Hillarious, workout,     |Sleep,     |</para>
   <para>|utility/    |Puppies,      |scenic driving,  |either Grammy or     |gov job (dental), famous,|work @home,|</para>
   <para>|incentives  |play doctor,  |high demand      |biggest audience     |Meme-ification           |comfortable|</para>
   <para>|            |kill kittens  |                 |you'll ever get      |                         |warm, zzzzzz.....</para>
   <para>+––––––––––––+––––––––––––––+–––––––––––––––––+–––––––––––––––––––––+–––––––––––––––––––––––––+–––––––––––+</para>
   <para>|            |Lots of blood,|smell w/o eating |paid in coins,       |demanding job; Once a    |NONE...EVER|</para>
   <para>|(opp.) cost |Your soul,    |=crazy,          |cold, competitive,   |Silly Walker, Always a   |           |</para>
   <para>|            |Hippocratic   |Bad neighborhood,|Jack the Music Critic|Silly Walker             |           |</para>
   <para>|            | Oath         |not paid greatly |                     |                         |           |</para>
   <para>+––––––––––––+––––––––––––––+–––––––––––––––––+–––––––––––––––––––––+–––––––––––––––––––––––––+–––––––––––+</para>
   <para>15. At any point where ∂production/∂worker - ∂cost/∂worker ≤ 0 AND {∂^2 production}/{∂worker^2} - {∂^2 cost}/{∂worker^2} &lt; 0</para>
   <para/>
   <para>p.126</para>
   <para>Demand (1) is the desire for a product and the ability to pay for it. According to the Law of Demand (2), when price decreases, demand rises, and when price increases, demand falls.</para>
   <para>Demand can be displayed in a table called a Demand Schedule (3) or on a graph called a Demand Curve (4). A Market Demand Schedule (5) is a table that shows how much demand all consumers in a market have. When that same information is displayed on a graph, it is called a Market Demand Curve (6).</para>
   <para>The different points on a demand curve show a Change in Demand (7). A Change in Quantity Demanded (8) occurs when consumers are willing to buy different amounts of a product at each price. The six factors that change demand are income, market size, consumer expectations, consumer taste, complement, and Substitute (9).</para>
   <para>The term Elasticity of Demand (10) describes how responsive consumers are to price changes. Demand that changes significantly when prices change is Elastic (11). Demand that doesn't change significantly when prices change is Inelastic (12). The dividing line between the two is where demand is Unit Elastic (13).</para>
   <para>Total Revenue (14) is calculated by multiplying price by quantity sold.</para>
   <para/>
   <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
         <para>The desire (or need) for a product and the ability to pay for it</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
         <para>They have a negative correlation </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
         <para/>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
         <para>If they expect an alternative that is sufficiently more attractive in some way, they will wait or go elsewhere to get that alternative</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
         <para>Elastic demand is demand that responds to price change more than the unit elastic and thus significantly responds to price change; Inelastic demand is demand that responds to price change less than the unit elastic and thus insignificantly responds to price change.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
         <para>quantity demanded(price)=q(p)=market demand curve; (1) Relative Elasticity at price p = percent change in quantity demanded / percent change in price =  relative change in quantity per relative change in price = (∂q(p)*p)/(∂p*q(p)). (2) Total Revenue=∑r=q(p), Absolute Elasticity=∂(q(p)*p)/∂p?</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
         <para>Computers go up while Stationery remains mostly stationary (Ba-Dum-tsss); Stationery's curve could be a dampened version of Computers' curve</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
         <para>???; electronic Stickies vs. real Stickies, IM vs. note runners, tablets vs. drawing, PGP key signing vs. stationery headers</para>
      </listitem>
   </orderedlist>
   <para/>
   <para>p.153</para>
   <informaltable frame="all">
      <tgroup cols="3">
         <colspec colnum="1" colname="c1"/>
         <colspec colnum="2" colname="c2"/>
         <colspec colnum="3" colname="c3"/><tbody><row>
            <entry>
               <para>You give each worker in your factory a specialized job</para>
            </entry>
            <entry>
               <para>Labor Productivity +</para>
            </entry>
         </row>
         <row>
            <entry>
               <para>Price of computer chips used in PDMPs rises (Ha!)</para>
            </entry>
            <entry>
               <para>Input Costs -</para>
            </entry>
         </row>
         <row>
            <entry>
               <para>New machinery speeds up the manufacturing process</para>
            </entry>
            <entry>
               <para>Technology +</para>
            </entry>
         </row>
         <row>
            <entry>
               <para>Your success prompts three new companies to start producing PDMPs</para>
            </entry>
            <entry>
               <para>Number of Producers -</para>
            </entry>
         </row>
         <row>
            <entry>
               <para>A new law requires producers to recycle the wastewater from their factories</para>
            </entry>
            <entry>
               <para>Government Action -</para>
            </entry>
         </row></tbody></tgroup>
   </informaltable>
   <para/>
   <para/>
</article>